## **Robert Taylor**

# Lead Game Developer, Lead Game Programmer, and Game Artist - Game Creation of Pathfinders

Portland, OR - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Robert-Taylor/fdce8a124a16f059

I'm a lead game designer and programmer of an indie game called Pathfinders. The Pathfinders team consists of two designers/programmers, two artists, and one musician. It's amazing to be working with this group where we are all able to put our expertise together to create a video game. Pathfinders has only been in production since June 2016, and we are excited to see where the game will go in the future.

I'm proficient at C#, C++, C, and Python. I have worked with many other languages as well, including PHP, JavaScript, HTML. I am a team-orientated worker who's confident in taking up a leadership role. I like helping with group decision making, problem-solving, team communication, conflict resolution, and help train people to make sure they are caught up with the rest of the group. I believe that when team members are comfortable with one another and confident in themselves an optimal work environment is formed.

My passion of game designing and programming have been a dream of mine since before entering elementary school. I have always wanted to create and work on a game that not only I can enjoy, but many other could enjoy as well. That's what I decided to dedicated my college life to obtaining a B.S. in Computer Science to help bring that dream to fruition.

When I am not working on Pathfinders or learning more about programming, I often spend my time online. This include playing games such as League of Legends, Overwatch, Hearthstone, or new releases for console (PS4, Xbox One). I also spend time hosting, help organize, and participate in LAN gaming tournaments.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Lead Game Developer, Lead Game Programmer, and Game Artist

Game Creation of Pathfinders - August 2016 to Present

- Collaborated with peers (two game developers/programmers, two graphic designers, one musician)
- Developed in Unity 5.5 using C#
- Worked in both individual programming and pair-programming environment
- Designed and created scripts that hold and stored game information (quest details, player stats, game stats), player controls,

in-game interaction, map generation, Artificial Intelligence for enemy interaction, dynamic UI system for animated text,

dynamic inventory system, dynamic equipment system, dynamic quest log, and display of player stats

- Use procedurally generated maps as the basis for the game world
- · Created basic sprites and resources
- Performed code optimization for CPU and Memory
- Designed and created storyboards to integrate a story into Pathfinders
- Experienced endless hours of debugging

### Beta Tester/QA

Bughouse Productions - January 2005 to Present

- Reviewed software UI, digital content, and applications
- Beta tested interactive animations, videos, quizzes

- Styled professional documents
- · Work with clients including Intel Education, Learning.com, Microsoft, and others

## Senior Capstone Project Pick-Up Game Organizer

- June 2015 to July 2016
- Worked in a team of four people (three Computer Scientist Engineers and a client)
- Directed software design, management, and development of Pick-Up Game Organizer while staying focused on and responsive

to the clients needs

- Collaborated with team member to prepare and organize professional documentation that outlined the project plan
- Used JavaScript, HTML, and PHP as the primary coding languages
- · Kept version control through Bitbucket and maintained communication with coworkers and client
- Maintained focus of the project throughout development: to create a web application users can use to create, manage, and find pick-up games

#### Barista

Starbucks - August 2011 to June 2012

making drinks and running the register

- · Opened Starbucks, including daily prep, such as making dripped and iced coffees and preparing pastries
- Closed Starbucks, including cleaning appliances and containers, balancing the till, and restocking inventory

## Courtesy Clerk, Baker, and Cashier

Starbucks - August 2011 to June 2012

Prepared breads, pastries, and cakes, restocked inventory, and closed Bakery (cleaned, organized the shelves and utensils,

and washed all dishes)

 Managed cash register, assisted customers, restocked, organized products, processed recycling, helped coworkers, bagged

customer groceries, and completed other support tasks as needed

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor's in Computer Science**

Oregon State University - Corvallis, OR 2012 to 2017

## **SKILLS**

C# (2 years), C (3 years), HTML5 (Less than 1 year), PHP (2 years)

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### Core Competencies

Software

- $\circ$  Windows OS  $\circ$  LaTeX  $\circ$  Unity 5.5  $\circ$  Bitbucket
- ∘ Office Suites ∘ Microsoft SharePoint ∘ Visual Studios ∘ Github

**Programming Languages** 

∘ C# ∘ C ∘ JavaScript ∘ Python

 $\circ$  C++  $\circ$  PHP  $\circ$  HTML5

## Work Traits

- $\circ$  Problem Solver  $\circ$  Leadership  $\circ$  Responsible  $\circ$  Dedicated
- $\circ$  Creativity  $\circ$  Team Orientated  $\circ$  Patient  $\circ$  Sense of Urgency